Guide to the Anne Loftis Papers, 1953-1978
Department of Special Collections
Anne Loftis Papers,
1953-1978
Special Collections M0306
Loftis, Anne.
4.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Anne Loftis, 1978.
Biographical Note
Anne Loftis was born in New York City in 1922 to Mary R. Nevins and the late historian Allan Nevins. She graduated from Smith College in 1944, then worked as a journalist and free-lance writer. She is the author (or co-author) of three books published by Macmillan:
The Great Betrayal: The Evacuation of Japanese-Americans During World War II, written with Audrie Girdner. 1969.
California, Where the Twain Did Meet. 1973.
A Long Time Coming: The Struggle to Unionize America's Farm Workers, written with Dick Meister. 1977.
She is also the author of numerous articles on ethnic groups and farm labor organizing. She is married to John Loftis, emeritus member of the Stanford English Department.
Scope Note
Papers consist of research materials gathered by Anne Loftis and compiled for the book which she co-authored with Dick Meister, A Long Time Coming. The collection includes correspondence, interviews and oral histories, notes, photographs, and printed material such as brochures, handbills, newsclippings, and pamphlets.
The papers document the various efforts to unionize America's farm workers during the twentieth century and include materials on major unions such as the National Farm Labor Union, the Southern Tenant Farmers Union, and the United Farm Workers of America.
In most instances, the original titles of folders have been retained.
Selected Index
Governor Jerry Brown (6/1, 2, 3, 4)
Cesar Chavez (1/8; 5/12)
Dr. Ernesto Galarza (1/10, 16, 26)
H.L. Mitchell (1/4, 21-26; 4/4-12)
Jean Simpson (1/3)
Reverend James L. Vizzard (1/4-7, 11)
Henry Wallace (1/12)
Senator Williams (5/9-12)
Abbreviations Used in Guide
AAA Agricultural Adjustment Administration
ACLU American Civil Liberties Union
AFL - CIO American Federation of Labor
AWOC Agricultural Workers Organizing Committee
IWW Industrial Workers of the World
NFLU National Farm Labor Union
STFU Southern Tenant Farmers Union
TFU Tenant Farmers Union
UFW United Farm Workers of America
USDA U.S. Department of Agriculture
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE REGARDING A LONG TIME COMING
  - Incoming, arranged alphabetically. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bliven, Bruce 12/23/69 - 9/16/75
    - Chambers, Pat 7/22/74
    - Donofrio, John 10/14/74
    - East, H. Clay 12/12/75
    - Fodell, Beverly 6/4/74
    - Foster, James nd
    - Fugita, Stephen 10/18/77
    - Gardiner, Polly 11/1/?
    - Graulich, Melody 6/5/74
    - Hart, James 6/3/77
    - Higgins, George 6/4/74
    - Hirasuna, Fred 3/28/74, 6/9/74
    - Honda, Harry 4/19/74
    - Land, Robert 6/10/74
    - McWilliams, Carey 7/26/78
    - Meier, Matt 4/4/74, 2/3/77
    - Miller, Sally 5/19/77
    - Mink, Patsy 11/21/74
    - Mitchell, H.L. (see folder 2, directly following)
    - Phillips, Hubert 3/29/75
    - Pillard, Vicky 1/27/78
    - Schacter, Leon 5/23/75, 6/6/75
    - Mitchell, H.L. 1/18/76 - 6/28/78 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Simpson, Jean 12/19/73 - 5/16/74? (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Vizzard, Rev. James 5/30/74 - 2/6/78 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Outgoing correspondence - 3/19/74 - 12/16/74 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing correspondence - 3/18/75 - 11/18/76 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Outgoing correspondence - 11/26/76 - 7/30/78 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- INTERVIEWS AND ORAL HISTORIES - used as sources in writing A Long Time Coming, arranged alphabetically.
  - Anderson, Henry, former staff official of AWOC, interview 5/12/75 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chavez, Cesar, speaking at Portola Valley 5/6/73,and at a gathering for financial support 5/6/73. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - De La Cruz, Jessie, oral history, 12/14/73Folder 18) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Galarza, Dr. Ernesto, interview, 5/7/74.(See also Box 1, Folder 18) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hasiwar, Hank, former organizer for the NFLU. Interview 6/30/75.Also included is xerox of TL to Hasiwar from Loftis. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hirasuma, Fred, active in Nisei League. Interview 6/13/74.
  - Jackson, Gardner (See Box 4, Folders 5,6,7)
  - McCullough, Rev. Thomas. Interview 5/29/75.
  - Phillips, Dr. Hubert. Interview 6/14/74.Also included: TL from Loftis to Phillips, 10/7/75,and clippings of Phillips' death, 7/76.
  - Smith, Chris and Dave, workers for UFW. Interview 1/28/74.
  - Toledo, Manuel, interpreted by Inez Mariner, 1/19/77.
  - Vera Cruz, Philip, Filipino vice president of UFW-AFL-CIO. Interview 9/11/74.
  - Vizzard, James L. Interview 6/23/75.
  - Wallace, Henry. Notes only from Henry Wallace, 1933-35,Vol. II. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yoneda, Karl and Elaine. Interview 4/8/74.Also included is TL from Loftis to Karl Yoneda, 10/7/75. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- OTHER RESEARCH MATERIALS:
  Correspondence, notes, excerpts, and miscellaneous (other than direct interviews) concerning people from whom Loftis received information for A Long Time Coming.
  - DiGiorgio, Joseph. DiGiorgio Farm Strike. Congressional records (xerox) of strike in general and of accounts given by Galarza (81st Congress) and notes taken from Galarza Collection (MS224). (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - DiGiorgio Strike (continued). Notes re Wendell reports and DiGiorgio libel suits (also taken from MS 224) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Galarza, Ernesto. TLS from Galarza to Loftis with photograph of Galarza, 2/23/76;questions for Dr. Galarza; AFL-CIO news release, 3/4/57;pp. 260-65 (xerox) of Barrio Boy; Univ. of Notre Dame press release of Farm Workers and Agri-business in California, 1947-1960;notes taken from Galarza Collection. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gannaway, David Molloy, president of Farmers Educational and Cooperative Union of Virginia. Brief biographical sketch and information regarding his papers. (See also Box 2, Folder 5) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lubin Simon J. From the Bancroft Library, notes taken mainly from letters, telegrams to and from Lubin, 1914-34 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mitchell, H.L., co-founder, historian STFU. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1) Writings of Mitchell:
      - A Message from a Friend; How I Became a Socialist; Little Known Farm Labor History; Recollections of a Southern Radical; Red Emma Passes at Toronto; Terror in Arkansas (incomplete)
    - 2) Correspondence of Mitchell to others, 7/22/76 - 7/21/78 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 3) Miscellaneous
      - a) Lists of his schedules and appearances, 1975-76;The California Democratic Socialist. 4/18/75 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - b) Publicity for his books and appearances (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - c) Personal: biographical sketch; questions for HLM by Anne Loftis; photograph of him and Hubert Humphrey; release for micro publication signed by Loftis; legal agreement from publisher (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - d) Publications not by Mitchell: The Green Rising, 1910-1977; What Socialism Is and What It is Not; excerpt (xerox) from Documentary Expression in Thirties America by William Scott; Presentation of the Clandening Award to H.L. Mitchell, 1949;Labor Studies Conference Opportunities, pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yoneda, Karl (See under Japanese Farm Workers, Box 2, Folders 31-33)
- VISUAL AND TOPICAL MATERIAL:
  - book jacket; xerox of the Introduction of the book; announcements of newly published A Long Time Coming; synopsis of the book from Washington Post, 6/12/77. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cartoon portraying American dislike of Chinese immigrants; map of California with its farm areas cited; three photographs, including ones with H.L. Mitchell and Ernesto Galarza (Box 1, Folder 26)
- AGRICULTURAL ISSUES
  - Big Farms Concept. FCL newsletter, 11/22, 5/73;testimony of the National Coalition for Land Reform to Senate Revenue and Taxation Commission on SB 1290, 7/26/72; Agriculture in California, 1966:Statement of the Directors of the Catholic Rural Life Conference, article on worsening conditions for farmers, 1970;interview with Gus Stamenson 9/6/72;testimony of Stamenson, 1/12/72;California Farmers Consumer Reporter, 12/68;pages from In Definite Battle: Steinbeck and California's Land Monopolists, statement of aims of the NCLR; clippings, 1970-75;notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - California Agriculture. The Beginning of Agriculture in California: Innovation vs. Continuity, by Rodman W. Paul, from California Historical Quarterly, Spring 1973(xerox) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Economic Studies. Seasonal Labor in California Agriculture, 1973,by John W. Mamer and Kuo-Shung Huang; Farm Labor in the U.S., by C. G. Bishop; Newsweek clipping, 11/15/75 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Economic Studies of the University of California. Oral History Center Proposed River Delta Project, with attached TLS to Loftis from A. I. Hickman; notes (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Farmers and Issues. History of the Sun-Maid Organization and Its Antecedents, booklet; The Condition of Farm Workers and Small Farmers in 1965,report to the National Sharecropper directors; FCL newsletter, 11/72;FCL Reporter Apr - May 1972;miscellaneous untitled pages (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Farmers and Issues (continued). clippings re hoof and mouth disease, 9/74;water pollution; misc. 1974-76 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Health and Welfare. Directory of Migrant Health Projects, bulletin. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Health and Welfare - Child Labor. NFWM newsletter, 6/77;clippings, 1972-74;list of statistics; TF from Rosemary Cooperider with small note to Anne Loftis. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Health and Welfare - Health and Work. Bulletin, Health of Farm Workers; notes; clippings 1969-74. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Health and Welfare - Housing. Self-help Enterprise, Inc. booklet; What Is the Story Behind the Napa Valley Wine Boycott? bulletin from UFW; interview with Feliciano Urrutia, 2/23/70; Self-help Enterprises, report No. 5, 12/15/65 - 2/15/66;clippings 1972-75. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Health and Welfare - Pesticides. Clippings, 1969-73; The Poisons We Eat, bulletin; notes (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Health and Welfare - Self-Help. Clippings. 1967-73. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mechanization. Notes on California Agricultural Mechanization Conference, 2/4/78;notes/clippings, 1977-78.See TLS from Vicky Pillard, Box 1, Folder 3. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Scabrook Farms. Articles, reference notes; The Scabrook Farms Story, booklet; The Condition of Farm Workers and Small Farms in 1963,report to the National Sharecroppers directors; FCL newsletter, 11/72;FCL Reporter, 4-5/72;miscellaneous untitled pages. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Statistics Today. California Manpower Indicator from the 1970Census, 2/72booklet; A Statistical Picture of California's Agriculture, booklet; notes; clippings, 1974-75. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Wages. Official California Dept. of Employment Division of Farm Labor Services - Chart of Statistics; Sharecroppers, Washington news report, 5/74;notes; clippings, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - World Food Problems. Magazine articles, 1974-75;report from Alan Cranston, U.S. Senator, 12/74 (Box 2, Folder 17 - 21)
- BRACERO PROGRAM
  - Introduction: Strangers to Our Fields - The National Farm Labor Union Fights the Bracero Program, by Anne Loftis; comments on Strangers, by U.N. Secretary (notes only); TFL re Southwest Labor History Conference, 1/27/75. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Braceros - Chronology. The Bracero Program in California: Political Development, Support and Expiration, by Sheldon Wylie, 5/20/67;employment tables and maps of foreign farm workers; notes. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Braceros - Depressing Wages and Replacing Domestic Workers - Notes. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bracero Grievances - notes. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bracero - Growers Violations - notes. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bracero - Strikebreakers - notes. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Demand for Braceros from Growers - notes. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Demand for Braceros in other states (than California)- Arkansas, Minnesota, Texas - Notes. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Demand for Braceros - Union vs. USES (U.S. Employment Services), xerox of questions for Dr. Galarza. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Demand for Other Foreign Workers. Questionnaire from Progrssive Growers Association of Santa Clara. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - End of Bracero era. Congressional Record (xerox); notes clippings, 1966-1967. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Legislative Hearings on Bracero Program - Agricultural Labor in the San Joaquin Valley, final reports and recommendations, 3/15/31(xerox). (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Legislative hearings (continued) - Congressional bills and articles pertaining to farm labor and migrating labor laws (xerox). (Box 3, Folder 13,14,15)
  - Legislative hearings (continued) - notes in spiral notebook. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- BRACEROS AND UNIONS
  - Unions against Braceros - notes. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Unions and Braceros - notes. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Union organization of Braceros - notes. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Union organization - attitudes of Big Labor; notes. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Union organization - CIO; notes. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Union organization - Cuban union; notes. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Union organization - Getting farm workers to join; notes. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Union organization - Growers vs. Unions; notes. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Union organization - Mexican attitudes; notes. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Union organization - NFLU; notes. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Unions vs. Labor Department. (Box 3, Folder 27)
- ILLEGALS, MIGRANTS, AND OTHER WORKERS
  - Domestic Workers - notes and clippings (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Domestic Workers - interstate recruitment; notes (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Later Migrants - Invisible Migrant Workers, by Dorothy Neiten, with photographs of The Lonely Migrant, by Richard Bellak, 4/77; The Migrant Worker, booklet from the League of Women Voters of California; Travel Patterns of Seasonal Farm Workers, 1961;miscellaneous notes; clippings, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Migrants (general) - notes (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Migrants - President Truman Commission - notes (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Illegals - Green Carders. Xerox, clippings, 1968-73 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Illegals Today. Misc. articles and clippings; notes 1972-75;See also correspondence from Alan Cranston and John Tunney (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Wetbacks. Notes (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Wetbacks - Abuses. Notes (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Wetbacks - Cultural Continuity. Songs of the Mexican Migration, by Paul S. Taylor; notes (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Wetbacks - Legalizing the Illegals; notes (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Wetbacks as strikebreakers; notes (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Wetbacks - Miscellaneous Articles. Evolution of Mexican Farm Labor Agreement of 1942; Interest Groups and Foreign Policy; Group Processes and the Era of Stabilization, the Bracero Program 1952-59; The State of the Unions, by Paul Jacobs. (Box 3, Folder 40)
- FARMERS
  - General Introduction. Farm Workers to Farmers; clippings, reports from the Center for Rural Studies (San Francisco); interview with David Brewer, 12/13/74;clippings (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1967-74;California farmer-consumer Reporter, 4-5/73;Rural Advance, winter /77 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Associated; notes from Galarza collection; clippings (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Farmers, Californian. Newspaper clippings, 1973-74;CFC Reporter clipping, 10-11/73;agricultural business - farmers in California (statistics) 1968; Agricultural Business, lecture by Charles Wollenburg, 10/1/74. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Farmers Union. Principles and Purposes of the Farmers Union, by L.M. Rhodes; A Few Facts for Farmers, by C.W. Brooks; The Revolt of the Farmers, by Charles E. Russel; notes taken from correspondence. (See also Box 1, Folder 19, for information on D.M. Gannavas) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- LABOR CONTRACTOR
  - Misc. notes; El Malcriado, 3/23/73;xerox from Los Angeles Times, 3/20/73 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- FARM WORKERS: Collection of various information re farm workers in general.
  - Comments on Farm Labor: interview with David Brewer, 12/15/74;clippings, 1974-75;notes (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Farm Worker Legislation: notes on farm labor legislation, such as the Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act, Migrant Health Act, Food and Nutrition Programs; OEO, Rural Legal Assistance, Office of Education (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers on farm worker legislation; their position on the legislation; news letters; written notes (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Xerox of various bills on public health, migrant labor camps, effective use of agricultural workers, privileges, payments (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Farm Worker Publications and Clippings: One Quarter Century of Farmer-Labor-Consumer Action, 1941-65;FCL newsletter, 4/73;church bulletin; California Farmer Consumer Reports, 10/68; Labor Contractor Law, 5/65;La Lucha, 5/75 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous clippings on farm workers, boycotts, etc., 1969-75 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Historical Perspective: notes on early strikes, current status of agricultural labor, farm labor, and the wars (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Packinghouse Workers: miscellaneous notes from magazines, papers, 1958-67 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sharecroppers: Rural Advance, Summer/74bulletin and pamphlets; Organic Training Farm Leads to Rural Renaissance, by Paul Good (Box 4, Folder 15)
- EARLY FARM WORKERS - (Nisei farm workers)
  - General, newspaper clippings, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bindlestiffs - notes (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chinese Early Farm Workers - clipping, 5/15/72;notes (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hindu Early Farm Workers - notes (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Japanese Early Farm Workers - (See also Box 1, Folder 13); notes and Box 4, Folders 32, 33, 34. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Labor Contractor Early Farm Workers - article from El Maleriado notes (Box 4, Folder 21)
- REGIONAL FARM WORKER, U.S.
  - Alabama: (sharecropper peonage) notes; clippings 1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Arizona, New Mexico: The Yardstick, by George Higgins, 7/72;Arizona Quarterly, Autumn/78;miscellaneous clippings, articles (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Arkansas: clippings, 1971, 1974, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Colorado: notes (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Florida: The Florida Christian Migrant Ministry, 3/73 and 9/72;testimony of Herbert Hill, Labor Secretary, NAACP, 11/5/63;record of suit by Florida workers against Florida agencies; miscellaneous clippings, 1974-75 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Iowa, Kansas, Louisiana, Michigan, New England, Ohio, Wisconsin: reference notes (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - New Jersey, New York: interview with David Pratt, Project Director, Migrant Health Services, 7/18/74;Suffolk County Relation Commission Report, 11/3/67; Migrant Protection Sought, news release, 1/31/68;miscellaneous clippings and articles, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Oregon, Texas, Utah: notes; clippings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Washington: notes (Box 4, Folder 30)
- REGIONAL FARMERS AND FARM WORKERS - FOREIGN
  - Jamaicans, Puerto Ricans: Puerto Rican newsletter, vol. 1, no. 1 (English and Spanish editions); statements of Clarence Senior and Alan Perl, Puerto Rican Department of Labor; notes. (See also ALS from Polly Gardner to Loftis, Box 1, Folder 3) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Japan (and Karl Yoneda): Yoneda, Personal: biographical sketches; xerox of I.D. and miscellaneous membership cards; We Salute the 45th Anniversary of Elaine Black and Karl Yoneda (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Works of Yoneda: History of Japanese Farm Labor in California, Heritage of Senator Katayama, poem Angel Island Detention Station (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Works of Yoneda (continued): 100 Years of Japanese Labor History in the USA; A Brief History of U.S. Asian Labor A Partial History of California Japanese Farm Workers; Rain, Rain, and Rain; Youth Never Dies (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Mexico: notes (Box 4, Folder 35)
- LEGISLATION
  - Governor Edmund G. Brown's Laws: Proposition 14-A Background Paper, 9/14/76;various letters, flyers, etc., commenting on Proposition 14; FL from Brown; misc. FLs from Cesar Chavez and others of AFL-CIO to Friends of the Farm Workers, 2/12/76;Alan Cranston (California Senator) to Anne Loftis; quotes from Rose Bird (Ca. Sec. of Agr.) speaking at Calif. History Society, 9/18/75;FCL newsletter, 11/75;flyers about boycotting of non-UFW grapes; The Teamster Raid: Stalled in the Vineyards, by George Baker; misc. mimeographs (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brown's Laws (continued): clippings, 1975-77 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brown's Laws (continued): Boycott Non UFW Grapes bumper sticker; articles, 1975-77 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Changes After Brown: misc. notes, xeroxed articles; TNA from Maia Krahl to Loftis, 2/27/77 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Wheatland Rift - 7/8/76,Loftis to Dick (?) re traveling through area of Wheatland field riot, with photographs, notes; misc. articles (Box 5, Folder 5,6)
  - Tolan Committee (ca. 1940):notebook #6 with the following: Wheatland (continued); IWW; court decision on Charlotte Whitney; Ford-Subr trial, investigation of Lop-field conditions; Douglas' memoirs of Yakima Farm Workers; hearings on Interstate Migration, 1940;H.L. Mitchell (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tolan (continued): notebook #7, congressional records interdispersed; Tolan Commission on Interstate Migration, 1940(Texas, Oklahoma, Arkansas, Oklahoma Tenant Farmers Union); California - The Dust Bowl Migrants, AFC opposition to FSA camps, Epworth League attempt to organize workers in camps (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Senator Williams Commission: notebook #3 - end of Washington hearings; hearing in Rio Grande, Texas; beginning of hearings in Monroe County (Rochester, NY). Notebook #4 - hearing with Robert Kennedy in Rochester; statistics on imports and exports; statement by Charles Gubson on CLRA and reply from AFSC; agricultural labor in Hawaii; report by William Friedland of Cornell on NY labor camp organization; hearings on H.R. 4769; misc. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Williams (continued): notebook #5 - H.R. 4769 (con'd), addition to Cesar Chavez' testimony; special arrangement for Puerto Rican farm workers; state right-to-work laws; summary of Arvin Dinuba Study; 1965-66Senate hearings (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Williams (continued): notebook #6 - continuation of hearings of Senate Subcommittee on Migratory Labor, 1965-66in Delano, CA; continuation of 1965-66hearings in San Antonio, TX; statement by Paul S. Taylor on CA agriculture; 1967report of the Commission on Labor and Public Welfare; article on Grapes of Wrath and criticism of In Dubious Battle; article by John Steinbeck in Nation; Mexican farm labor agreement of 1942.Notebook #2 - summary of Senate hearings on 5.8 (Migratory Labor Legislation) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Williams (continued): misc. articles: The Farmers Arise, reprint 6-9/66re Starr Co. strike and Senate hearings and analysis of strike; injunction against picketing by UFW, Congressional Record, 1967;Congressional Record-Senate (including testimony by Cesar Chavez) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Court Action: U.S. Supreme Court report - petition for a writ of certiorari, 10/73;plaintiff- appellant brief; record of UFW organizing committee vs. Texas ranges and sheriffs (specific ones listed); report at the Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1955;notes; clippings, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- UNIONS
  - AWOC reference notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Inter Union Strife and misc. strikes notes (Box 6, Folder 2)